The most savage film in history!
Soldier Blue is a western, drama film directed by Ralph Nelson.
After a cavalry group is massacred by the Cheyenne, only two survivors remain: Honus, a naive private devoted to his duty, and Cresta, a
young woman who had lived with the Cheyenne two years and whose sympathies lie more with them than with the US government.
Together, they must try to reach the cavalry's main base camp.
As they travel onward, Honus is torn between his growing affection for Cresta.
Kathy Maribel Lee, 'Cresta', played by Candice Bergen.
Honus Gent, played by Peter Strauss.
Isaac Q. Cumber, played by Donald Pleasence.
Col. Iverson, played by John Anderson.
Spotted Wolf, played by Jorge Rivero.
Capt. Battles, played by Dana Elcar.
Soldier Blue is a 1970 American revisionist Western film directed by Ralph Nelson
and starring Candice Bergen, Peter Strauss, and Donald Pleasence.
Adapted by John Gay from the novel Arrow in the Sun by T.
Olsen, it is inspired by events of the 1864 Sand Creek
massacre in the Colorado Territory.
Nelson and Gay intended to utilize the narrative surrounding the Sand Creek
massacre as an allegory for the contemporary Vietnam War.
Released in August 1970, the film drew attention for its frank
depictions of violence, specifically its graphic final sequence.
Some film scholars have cited Soldier Blue as a critique of America's "archetypal art form [the Western],"
with other interpretations ranging from it being an anti-war picture to an exploitation film.
The film explores themes of based on novel or book,
attack, massacre, private, wild west.
The tone is emotional.